thefabricofourlives.com 2011-12-09

# Cotton: The Fabric of Our Lives

Privacy Policy

Cotton Incorporated endeavors to protect your online privacy while providing you with the most useful and enjoyable Web experience possible. Users can access many features on our sites anonymously, however you may be asked to provide personal information when participating in contests, surveys or providing feedback or when using other interactive areas of our sites. Use of our sites signifies your understanding and acceptance of the terms of this privacy policy. Please review the legal terms and conditions of our web sites for additional information regarding disclaimers, limitations of liability and other important information.

**How we collect and use personal information**  
Cotton Incorporated is the sole owner of the information collected on our sites. We collect information from our users at several different points on our sites. In general, each user has access to all the information and features available on our sites. However, users electing to participate in certain areas of the site, for example sweepstakes, contests and surveys, will be asked to provide specific user information. Also, we reserve the right, for any reason, in our sole discretion, to terminate, change, suspend or discontinue any aspect of our sites, including, but not limited to, content, features or hours of availability, and to impose limits on certain features of our sites or restrict your access to part or all of our sites without notice or penalty.

**Site Registration**  
Users electing to register with our sites will be prompted to provide contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information, for example, to contact the user about services on our sites for which he/she has expressed interest. It is generally optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers (such as username and password), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our sites.

**Surveys & Contests **  
From time-to-time our sites request information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose such information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used, for example, to notify the winners and award prizes and may, from time to time, be used to provide unsolicited gifts from Cotton Incorporated. Survey information will be used, for example, for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of our sites. Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties other than as set forth in this privacy policy. Though we may use an intermediary or outsourcer to conduct these surveys or contests, they will not be authorized to use users' personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our sites, we will request the friend's name and email address. Cotton Incorporated will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit our sites. Cotton Incorporated stores this information for the purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. The friend may contact Cotton Incorporated webmaster@cottoninc.com to request that the information not be retained in our database. 

**Profile**  
We store information about individual users that we collect through direct prompting. The stored information is used to create a profile that details her/his viewing preferences. Consequently, information collected is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content on our sites for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web sites, and to direct pertinent marketing information and promotions to them. Other than as set forth in this privacy policy, we do not share your individual profile with other third parties and any information released will be in aggregate form only and will not reveal any personal information about individual users.

**How we protect your personal information**  
Any personal data you enter on our web sites when registering for contests, survey's, feedback, etc. is collected and stored in a database. Cotton Incorporated will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. Only authorized Cotton Incorporated employees and agents have access to the data. Cotton Incorporated employees and agents will not share information with any third parties outside Cotton Incorporated, other than as set forth in this privacy policy. Notwithstanding the above, due to the open nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that any information stored on our servers, or transmitted to or from a user, will be free from unauthorized access. By using our sites, you acknowledge that you understand and agree to assume these risks.

**How we use "cookies" and other technologies**  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that some Web sites store on your computer's hard drive when you visit their Web sites. Like many other Web sites, our sites use cookies, for example, to identify registered users so they may not have to enter personal information upon each visit. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies but allow you to modify security settings so you can approve or reject cookies on a case-by-case basis. 

As with many Web sites, we also may use other technology (e.g., web bugs, e-mail bugs, clear GIFs, web beacons and tracker GIFs) in our web sites and/or in our communications with you to enhance the functionality of our sites and to make your transactions and other activities more convenient and efficient (collectively, â€œTracking Technologiesâ€�). These technologies may be used by us to store and collect information relating to your viewing and use of our sites and our correspondences with you. We also may collect your IP (Internet Protocol) address to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our site and identify our users. 

Third parties (including, but not limited to, software vendors, advertisers, content providers and fulfillment companies) may also use Tracking Technologies by or through our sites. We have no control over what information such third parties track or collect, and we have no responsibility or liability for any tracking, data collection or other activities of such third parties. 

**Communications from the Site**

**Special Offers and Updates**  
We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, contest announcements, surveys and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out section.

**Newsletters**  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter or mailing, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out section.

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

**Customer Service**  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account. We will generally correspond with users via email or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes.

**Choice/Opt-out**  
Our users are generally given the opportunity to â€˜opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, contest forms have an â€˜opt-out' mechanism so users who participate in contests, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email. We also offer an opt-out mechanism on the registration page or the user may contact us by email at any one of our sites. (If you use more than one e-mail address, then send your opt-out e-mail from each of your e-mail addresses.)

Notwithstanding the above, your option not to receive promotional and marketing material shall not preclude us from corresponding with you, by e-mail or otherwise, regarding your existing or past relationship with us (e.g., your account activity or our responses to questions or inquiries you pose to us), and shall not preclude us from accessing and viewing your personal information in the course of maintaining and improving our sites.

**What we provide to third parties**  
Our sites generally do not provide access to your personal information to third parties. However, we may provide third parties with aggregate statistics about traffic patterns, and related site information. This data reflects site usage patterns gathered during millions of customer visits to our web sites each month, but it does not contain behavioral, profile, or identifying information about any personally identified individual user. We also may transfer, sell or assign your personal information to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of assets, reorganization or liquidation, and we reserve the right to disclose any information concerning you if required by law or to protect or defend our rights or the rights or well-being of our users or if you are involved (or are reasonably suspected to be involved) in any illegal activity, even without a subpoena, warrant or court order.

**Postings and Public Areas**  
You are solely responsible for the information and other content you post on or through our sites. You understand that personal and other information (e.g., user name, e-mail address, phone number) that you post on or through public areas of the sites (e.g., chat, bulletin boards) are generally accessible to, and may be collected and used by, others and may result in unsolicited messages or other contact from others. Users of our sites are encouraged to exercise caution when providing personal information about themselves.

If you elect to use our referral service to inform a third party about our sites, or if you otherwise provide a third party's personal information to us or to the sites, you warrant that you have permission to do so and you agree to indemnify, defend and hold harmless Cotton Incorporated and its affiliates from and against any claim, liability, cost and expense arising in any way therefrom.

**How we handle links  **  
Our sites contain links to other sites and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. In most cases users will be prompted when leaving our sites.

**Obtaining your consent**  
By using our sites, you give Cotton Incorporated permission to collect information about the pages served to you as an anonymous user for the purpose of calculating aggregate site statistics. If you register at any of our sites, you authorize Cotton Incorporated to use the information you provide to personalize the information we deliver to you and to use your demographic information when calculating aggregate user data.

If you are under 13 years old, you must not provide your name, e-mail address, or any other identifying information without the consent of your parent or guardian, or as otherwise provided for by applicable law. Verification of parent and guardian must be provided. You represent and warrant that you are domiciled in the United States.

Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the registration page or by emailing us at any one of our sites.

**Notification of Changes**  
In the event our privacy policy should materially change, we will post those changes on this privacy statement, with a notice thereof on the homepage of our sites and in other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

In general, we will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. If, however, we decide to use or disclose users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will generally notify users via email prior to such use or disclosure of any such information. Users will have the opportunity to opt-out of any change in the use of their information. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used or disclosed in this new manner. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary above, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will merely post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes means you accept those changes. In some cases where we post such a notice, we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

**Tell us what you think**  
Cotton Incorporated welcomes your questions and comments about our privacy policy. Please send email to [webmaster@cottoninc.com](mailto:webmaster@cottoninc.com) 

**Last updated: August 27, 2007**  
Disclaimer: This policy is not a substitute for legal advice. If you have legal questions related to this policy, consult an attorney.
